<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-25T08:29:37+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Eugen Ciur</title><subtitle>Fantastic blog!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On Simple Skills</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/intro/2019/09/24/simple-skills-chess.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Simple Skills" /><published>2019-09-24T08:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-09-24T08:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/intro/2019/09/24/simple-skills-chess</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/intro/2019/09/24/simple-skills-chess.html">![chess](/assets/chess.png)

One can learn basic chess theory in matter of days or at most couple of weeks of youtube videos on the subject; maybe one or two books will help as well.

However, what I find absolutely amazing is how much training is necessary to
truly master the game. By mastering the game I mean having [ELO rating](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chess_rating_system#Elo_rating_system) of 
say 1800. For me, following a moderate self-taught training, I needed 2 years
to increase my ELO number by 200 points - from a weak 1300 to a strong 1500
(for classical games with 15 minutes per side and 15 seconds increment).
I think I will need another 10 years of training to bypass ELO 2000.

It is fascinating - for such a simple skill as game play, a person needs
around 10 or 12 years of training (with only a minimal theory) to master
the subject.

What about more complex skills - how much time of training (let alone theory) is necessary to really master computer programming? What about
mastering the subject of how to implement distributed network computer systems? Compilers? Operating systems?</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello, Internet!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/intro/2019/06/01/hello-internet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, Internet!" /><published>2019-06-01T08:41:51+02:00</published><updated>2019-06-01T08:41:51+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/intro/2019/06/01/hello-internet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/intro/2019/06/01/hello-internet.html">We live in a fantastic world, a world where information is distributed way faster
than it can be assimilated: in a snap of fingers  new ideas are delivered to the
whole planet, howerver, it takes days, months or even years that those same ideas 
to be learned and well understood.</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We live in a fantastic world, a world where information is distributed way faster than it can be assimilated: in a snap of fingers new ideas are delivered to the whole planet, howerver, it takes days, months or even years that those same ideas to be learned and well understood.</summary></entry></feed>